

# **OXANA THEIS**

#### FRONTEND WEB DEVELOPER

**Tel**: +33 7 66 86 89 48

Mail: otheis@protonmail.com

**Portfolio**: https://oth21dev.github.io/portfolio/ **GitHub**: https://github.com/OTH21DEV

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/oxana-theis-417922158/

Frontend Developer with a strong focus on responsive web applications using React. Over 11 years of B2B IT and Telecom experience, enhancing user experience and delivering practical solutions. Proficient in Webflow for rapid prototyping.

# **SKILLS**

Frontend Development: JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML5, CSS3, React, Redux, Sass, Recharts library

Web Design: Webflow, Figma

Backend Development (familiar): Node.js, Express, MongoDB, MySQL

Development Tools: Swagger, JSDoc, GitHub, Heroku, Command line tools, Package managers

Soft skills: effective communication, problem solving, teamwork, time management, customer focus, attention

to detail, adaptability, negotiation, continuous learning

Languages: English, French, Russian

# RELEVANT PROJECTS

### **Corporate social network - Fullstack Development**

https://corporate-social-network-902adf387c2e.herokuapp.com/

- Description: Full-stack development with Node.js, Express, MySQL, and React.
- Highlights: RESTful APIs, Cloudinary media integration, responsive frontend.

### **Corporate Website - Frontend Development**

https://www.lavcraft.com/

- **Description:** Developed a professional ccompany website using React
- Highlights: Multi-page design (landing, about, contact), responsive layouts, cross-browser compatibility, web accessibility.

### Search Engine - Frontend Development - Vanilla Javascript

https://oth21dev.github.io/OxanaTheis 7\_02012022/

- Description: Developed using Vanilla JavaScript.
- Highlights: Clean HTML/CSS, dynamic UI, fast search algorithms.

## **EXPERIENCE**

### 03.2024-present Freelance Frontend & Webflow developer

- Work: Developed various web applications using React and Webflow
- Skills: Enhanced skills in responsive design, user experience, and modern web technologies

### 05.2023-02.2024 Purple Core Engineering-Frontend web developer, Remote - USA, Wyoming

- Work: Developed IOCs monitoring interfaces using React and JavaScript.
- **Skills:** Responsive design, real-time tools, data visualization, performance optimization.

2011-2022 Telkea Group - Account manager - Luxembourg, Luxembourg

2010-2011 World Trade Center - Account manager - France, Metz

2006-2008 PSK Logistics - Account manager - Russia, Saint-Petersburg

# **EDUCATION**

### 2023 - Application developer - OpenClassrooms

2010 Master Degree of Management - Business institute

2006 Master Degree of Management - University of Economics and Business